Guide to the Henry Taube Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Henry Taube papers
1941-2003
SC0731
Taube, Henry, 1915-2005
64.5 Linear feet (53 boxes)
Collection pertains to his teaching and research, primarily while at Stanford University, and includes grant files, articles and papers, reprints, class files, correspondence, travel records, and biographical materials.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Born in Canada, Henry Taube received his B.S. in chemistry at the University of Saskatchewan in 1935, and his Ph.D. in Chemistry from Berkeley in 1940. He was an Instructor at Berkeley, Assistant Professor at Cornell, rose to Professor at the University of Chicago, and in 1962 came to Stanford University. At Stanford he served as chair of the Department of Chemistry from 1972-74 and again in 1978-79. Henry's research interests were in both inorganic and organic chemistry; his work has been central to many different fields such as electron transfer at semiconductor electrodes, solar energy conversion, and photosynthesis. For his great contributions to science, Henry received numerous honors, including membership in the National Academy of Sciences (1959), The National Medal of Science (1977), The Priestley Medal (1985, the highest award of the American Chemical Society) and the Nobel Prize in Chemistry (1983). He died in November 2005.
Description of the Collection
Collection pertains to his teaching and research, primarily while at Stanford University, and includes grant files, articles and papers, reprints, class files, correspondence, travel records, and biographical materials.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Department of Chemistry. Faculty.; Taube, Henry, 1915-2005; Chemistry, Inorganic.; Chemistry--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2005-008
  - Published manuscript files
    - From Electron Transfer Reactions to the Effects of Backbonding, Taube (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Properties of Ion Clusters: Interactions of [Ru(Nh3)5…with Vassiliki. G. Poulopoulou (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Kinetic Effects in Outer Sphere: V. Poulopoulou and H. Taube (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Osmium Complexes of 1,4,7-triaza-cyclononane (tcn)… Ware, Taube, Olmstead (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Speciation of V(II) Salts in Pyridine and Acetonitrile as Solvents. Ghosh, Taube, Hasegawa, Kuroda (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Speciation of V(II) Salts – References, Ghosh (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Anomalies in the Kinetics of Substitution… Poulopoulou, Takahashi, Hasegawa (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Synthesis, Characterization, and Crystal Structure of Hydroxyruthenocene. Kirchner, Kwan, and Taube (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Comparisons of the Rates of Substitution in… V. Poulopolou, Z.-W.Li, H. Taube (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Determination of the Structure of…. Hasegawa, Li, Parkin, Hope, McMullan, Koetzle, and Taube (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - [Os(NH3)4n2,n1-(CH2=CH-CO2H)2]2+-Preparation, Characterization, Nunes, Taube (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Synthesis, Characterization and Electro-chemistry of New Tetra and… Nunes and Taube (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Dihydrogen as a Co-ligand in Substitution and Cis/trans-isomerization Reactions, Li and Taube (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Reactions of the Ion Pair [Os(NH3)6]3+… Poulopoulou and Henry Taube (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Extension of the Preparation of New Osmium Species to the cis-Tetraamine Moiety. Li, Harman, Lay, and Taube (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Dihydrogen Complexes of Tetraamineosmium(II) with Carbene as Co-Ligand… Li and Taube (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Monodydrido Complexes of Os(IV) Amines of Coordination Number Seven. COMM. Li, Yeh, and Taube. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Equilibrium and Kinetic Behavior…. Andrade, Dec. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Oxidation of Water Coordinated to Cobalt III. Thusius, Dec 1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Tracer Experiments of Oxidation… Ox. Acid by Ce(IV) Andrade, Nov. 65 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Problems of Reactivity in Classical Chemical Systems. March 1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Reactivity, Inc (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Properties of (4-aminopyridine) pentaamminerruthenium(II) and (III). Jim Sutton (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - How Redox Reactions Take Place. H. Taube for CHEMISTRY (ACS Applied Publications.0 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Inorganic Reaction Mechanisms, Conf. on: "Bridging Groups in Electron Transfer. Reactions." U. of Kansas, 6/64++ (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - S to O and O to S Linkage Isomerization in Sulfoxide complexes of Pentaamine Ruthenium. A. Yeh, N. Scott, H. Taube (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Andrade, Carlos (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Green (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - New Coordination Chemistry of Saturated Ligands. H. Taube (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - The Electron Transfer Reactions of Some Derivatives of Pentaammine-pyridine Ruthenium(II) and Ruthenium(II) (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Jones (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Pentaammine Complexes of Osmium with pi Acceptor ligands – Judy Sen (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Experimental Approaches to Electronic Coupling in Metal Ion Redox Systems. H. Taube—Tunneling Conference in Philadelphia. Nov. 1977 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Intramolecular Electron Transfer (II): bis(4-pyridyl)methane as Bridging Group. Konrad Rieder, Henry Taube (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Andrade (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Andrade, et al. Exchange of Oxygen… (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Binuclear Ion………Harrison, Weissberger, Taube. 1967 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Kruse (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Appelman, E.H. (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Baldwin (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Ford/Rudd/Gaunder/Taube……Ru(II)………1967 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - (Ru(NH3)5N22+ in AQUEOUS SOLTN. Harrison, Taube 1967 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Cr+++Ox (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Isotope Effects on Aquation (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Kinetic and Tracer Studies w/Jordan May 1966 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Oxygen Tracer Studies on…Cobalt (III) Carbamate Complexes. With A.M. Sargeson. January, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Meyer Paper 2-68 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Ozone ms. Foschermer (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Murmann (1954) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Posey (1953) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Wilson – Ga+++, Cr+++ (1952) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - ROSEO Exchange (1952) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Hunt and Taube (Peroxide, etc.) (1952) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Chem. Rev., 1952 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - A Determination of the Solvation Number of the Magnesium Ion…(With J. H. Swinehart) 1962 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Relative Acidity Study (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Freser (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Oxygen Isotopic Effects on Rectn. Of Aquo-Diebler, Dodel May 1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Isotopic Fractionation…..Green, Shug March 1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Acid Hydrolysis of Ethyl Glycinate Complex of Pentaammineruthenium(III) A. Yeh (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Electron Transfer Catalysis of Substitution. Dan Geselowitz (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - On the Reactivity of Imidazoliumrutheniumammine Complexes: Nitrogen to C-Bound, etc… Michael Tweedle (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Manifestation of Sulfur to Sulfur Through-Bond Interactions in Complex Ion Spectra (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Advances in Inorganic Chemistry and Radiochemistry (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Monodentate Form of Malonatochromium(III) Hutchital June 1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Schweier, et al (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Product Competition Ratios in June Substitution Reactions Dolbear 1966 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Electron Transfer Reactions – Aug. Chelating Bridging Broups – Butler ‘65 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Preparation and Properties..Pent. Cobalt(III) Jorden-Sargeson Nov. 65 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Some Photochemical Reactions of O3 in the Gas Phase (With D. Katakis) 1961 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Malonate as a Bridging Group for Electron Transfer (With G Svatos) 1961 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Activation Effects and Rates of Electron Transfer (With RTM Fraser) 1960 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Remote Attack and Ester Hydrolisis on Electron Transfer (With RTM Fraser) (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Reaction of Glyoxyl…..Cobalt III Price Aug. 1966 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Esperman (?) (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Hunt, JB (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Arius, et all – Luikage (?) (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Olson, et al. Hydration…. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Andrade, Jordan. Exchg. Of O… (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Tracer Studies on the Oxidation of Pb(II) by H2O2. (With U. Agarwala & M. Anbar) 1962 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Some Observations of Electron Transfer in Solution (Presented at Brookhaven Nat. Lab., June 1962) (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Redox Reactions of Complex Ammines of Ru(II)-Ru(III). With John F Endicott. Submitted: November 1962 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Oxygen-17 NMR Shifts Caused by Cr++ in Aqueous Solutions (With Jackson and Lemons). 1962 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - The Reaction s of Iodopentamminecobalt(III) with Various One-Electron Redox Reagents (With Haim) 1962 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - The Exchange of Methanol between Solvated Cations and Solvent. I. (With T Rogers and J Swinehart 1962) (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Kinetics of the Reduction of Halopentaaminecobalt(III) Complexes…H. Diebler and H. Taube. Dec 1964 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Studies on Phosphato and Methylphosphato Complexes…Willfred Schmidt and Henry Taube. December 1963 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Hydrogen Tracer Studies on the Reactions of Uranium Hydride…John B. Hunt & Henry Taube. December 1962 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Breck-WP. UV. (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Arieeor – Bimolecular (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Sulfone & Ester Ligands……Hurst and Taube 1967 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - The Reaction of O(1D) with CO2 at Low Temperatures. 1967 Weissberger, Breckenridge, Taube (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Maspero et al, Aquarhodium(II) Ion (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Scheidegger, et al (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Andrade & Taube C2O42- (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Olson, Kanazawa, Taube (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - RDCTN+ By METAL IONS OF FUMARATO…..HURST&TAUBE 1967 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Stritar-Electron Transfer Reactions Ru(III) (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Electron Transfer WWF Frenor 1969 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Catalysis in Substitution on Ru(II) by Iodide – David Richardson (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Crystal Structures of cis-Tetraaminebis(isonicotinamide)ruthenium(II) and (III) Perchlorate. David Richardson, Darrel Walker, James Sutton, K. Hodgson (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - On the Observation of Bands in the Near Infrared by CR Wilson and H Taube (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Jones – Matrix Isolation (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Disulfur Binuclear Rutheniumammines by Christa Brulet, Stephen Isied, and H Taube (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Rates of Intramolecular Electron Transfer by Stephan S Isied and Henry Taube (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Carbon-Bound Imidazolium Ylides as Ligands in Ru(II) and Ru(III) Complexes by RJ Sundberg, RE Shepherd, and H Taube (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Studies on Substitution Reaction of Aquopentaamineruthenium(II) Rex E Shepherd and H Taube (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Oxidation of Coordinated Ammonia to Coordinated Dinitrogen. John Buhr (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Dinitrogen Complexes of Osmium(III) Haloammines. John Buhr, 2nd Paper (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Holwerda, Deutsch, Taube, Kinetic Study (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Evidences for a Biner clear Nitrous Oxide (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Mixed Oxidation States in Osmium Ammine Dinitrogen Complexes, Roy H Magnuson and Henry Taube (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Creutz – M Nitrogens (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Reduction of Oxygen by Hexaammineruthenium(II) and by Tris-Ethylenediamineruthenium (II), JR Pladziewicz, JA Broomhead, and H Taube (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Reduction of p-Formyl and m-formyl-benzoatopentaamminecobalt(III) by Metal Cations (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Binuclear Complexes of Ruthenium Ammines – Carol Creutz and Henry Taube (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Raichart – RU(II) (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Characterization and Reactions of Osmium (IV) Ammines, John Buhr and Jay Winkler – First paper (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Stereoselectivty in Electron Transfer Reactions – Daniel Geselowitz (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - The Reduction of Oxygen by Ruthenium(II) Ammines, David Stanbury, Otto Haas (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Manifestations of Sulfur to Sulfur through Space Interactions in Complex Ion Spectra, cy stein (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Pentaammineruthenium Dimethyl Cogenide Complexes –Cy Stein (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Rutehniumammines Disulfides – Cy Stein (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Ligand to Metal Charge Transfer Absorption of Coordinated Disulfide, CA Stein (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - The Trimethylsulfonium Ion as a Ligand: Synthesis and Characterization of [(NH3)5RuS(CH3)3](PF6)3, CA Stein and Henry Taube (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Lash paper (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Deutsch (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Schmido (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Tracer Experiments on Alkaline Hydrolysis of Oxalate Ammonia (With C. Andrade; October 1963) (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Mixed-Valence Molecules: Electronic Delocalization and Stabilization… David E Richardson (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - A Redetermination of the Hexaammine-cobalt(III)/(II) Electron Self-Exchange Rate. A. Hammershoi, D. Geselowitz (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Determinations of the Comproportionation Constant for a Weakly Coupled… Jim Sutton, Patrick Sutton (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Acid Catalysed Aquation of Hexaammineruthenium(II) (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Conversion of Osmacyclopentatriene to Osmahexatriene via 1,2 Hydrogen Shift. Pu, Hasegawa, Parkin, Taube (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Communication: Osmiacyclopentatriene Complexes: Structural Characterization. Pu, Hasegawa, Parkin, Taube (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Synthesis, Characterization and Reactivity of. Kirchner, Taube, Scott, and Willett (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - A Versatile Recognition Probe… Li and Taube (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Aspects of N2 binding by Osmiumammines. Henry Taube (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - The Reduction of [Os(NH3)5… Hasegawa, Kwan, Taube (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Synthesis and Reduction of Osmium (VI) Nitrido Complexes and the X-Ray Crystal… Ware and Taube (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Syntheses of Pentaammine Osmium(III) and Osmum (II) Complexes: Pentaammine (trifluoromethansulfonato-0)Osmium(III) Lay, Magnuson, Taube (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Molecular Hysterisis (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Modulation of Physical and Chemical Properties of N-H2, Complexes of Osmiumammines by Facile Substitution. Li and Taube (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Extension of the Preparation of New Osmium Species to… Li, Harman, Taube (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - "Pentaamineosmium(II)-n2-2,6-lutidine: an intermediate for C-H activation." Rossella Cordone and Henry Taube (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Electronic Effects of bis-Acetylacetone in Ru(II) and Ru(III) Complexes--Hasegawa, Lau, Taube, and Schaefer (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Allyl (?—handwriting confusing) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Preparation and Characterization of Bispentaamineosmium(II) Pyrene Complex—Hasegawa, Sekine, Schaefer, Taube (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Arene-to-Alkyne Linkage Isomerizations of Diphenylacetylene on Pentaaminsosmium—Harman, Wishart, and Taube (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Isostructural n2 –Dihydrogen Complexes [Os(NH3)5(H2)+n… (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Reactions of Hexachloroosmate(IV) with Hydrazine Monohydrate: Syntheses and Properties of Pentaammine(dinitrogen)-osmium(II) Chloride…Peter A. Lay and Henry Taube (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Substituent Effects on n2-Coordinated Arene Complexes of Pentaamineoosmium(II.) Harman, Sekine, and Taube (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Substitution Induced N-N Coupling for Nitride Coordinated to Osmium (IV)—Ware, Taube, Bino, Cohen (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - "Synthesis of [Os(NH3)5(n2-TMB)]2+:: A Valuable Precursor for Pentaammineosmium(II) Chemistry." W. Dean Harman, Henry Taube. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - The Selective Hydrogenation of Benzene to Cyclohexene on Pentaamineosmium(II), Harman and Taube (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - n-Heterocyclic Complexes of Pentaamine-osmium(II) and the Metal-Induced Cyclo-addition of Pyrrole and Maelic Anhydride—Cordone, Harman, Taube (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Pyrazine-Bridged Complexes. Synthesis and Spectroscopic Studies on Binuclear Pyrazine….Lay, Magnuson, Taube Paper #10 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Carbon-Hydrogen Bond activation in novel n2-bound cationic…Cordone, Harman, and Taube (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Redox Promoted Linkage Isomerizations of Aldehydes and Ketones on Pentaammine-osmium, WD Harman, M Sekine, and H Taube (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Wm Valley In Progress (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Research Correspondence: M – Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Binuclear Ruthenium Complexes Bridged by the Dicyanamide Anion… J.E. Sutton, H. Crentzien, and HT (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Oxidation Chemistry of Decamethylruthenocene. Terry Smith (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Publication – CA Stein & Block (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Wishart – Work in Progress (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Linkage Isomerization in Pentaamine-ruthenium Complexes of Amides Fairlie, Ilan, and Taube (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Mixed Valence Molecules – Wishart and Lyon NOTES FOR A SEMINAR (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Levin (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Ester Hydrolysis…….Hutchital July 1965 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Isotopic Discrimination of Some Solutes Viste – July 1966 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Gleit (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Manganic Ion Equil. (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Investigation PFV(II)-V(III) Couple, Bennett & Taube 1967 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Kinetics of Some Outer Sphere Electron Transfer Reactions. J.F. Endicott & Henry Taube. December, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - The Reactions of Metal Oxides with Cr+2aq. With B.A. Zabin. January, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - The Role of Dissolved Lithium in the Reaction between Triethylsilane and Ethylamine. A. Viste & H. Taube, 12/63 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Electron Transfer through Organic Structural Units (With E. Gould; October 1963) (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Formation of Co(NH3)5X++ Complexes….(With Albert Haim.) Submitted: June 6, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Bond Fission in the Base Hydrolysis…With m. Green. Submitted: March 1963 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Isotopic Fractionation in the OH-/H2O Exchange Reaction. Michael Green and Henry Taube. March, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - The Reactions of Iodopentammine-cobalt(III) with Various "Two-electron" Oxidizing Agents. Haim&Taube March 1963. (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - The Mechanism of Base Hydrolysis of Substituted Pentammino Cobaltic Complexes (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Cahill – Peroxide Paper (1951) (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Halperin and Taube (IV) (1951) (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Plane and Taube (Final) (1951) (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Co(III) – Mag. Susc. (1951) (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Hunt – Me+++aq (1951) (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Sebera (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Oxidation of Aquopentaammine & of Hexaammine Cobalt (III) Ions – Thusius & Taube 1967 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - OXDTN+ of p-HYDROXYMETHYL…..Robson & Taube 1967 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Mech. Of Reaction of Carbonatopent. Cobalt (III)…Jordan, Sargeson Oct. 65 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - RDCTNS. PENTAA…SUBS. PYRID. Nordmeyer and Taube 1967 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - REDCTN. CARBONYLCARBOXYLIC ACID (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Creutz, Carol, et al. (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Alan B Hoffman (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Saffir & Taube – The Oxidation of Captive Oxalate (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Halogen + MN(II) (1950) (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Cl Exch (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Chemical Shifts in NMR Absorbtion (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Consultant/Lecturer Payment Certification (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Molecular Hysterisis Revisited Sano and Taube (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Nitrile Complexes of Pentaammineosmium (II) and (III). Sekine, Harman, and Taube (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - The Stereoselective Electron Transfer Reactions of Ethylenediaminetetraacetatocobalt(III)ate…. Geselowitz, Hammershoi, and Taube (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - The Redox-Catalyzed Condensation of Hexaammineosmium (II) with Acetone, Harman and Taube (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Decaammine (mu-dinotrogen-N,N') diosmium(III): Synthesis, Characterization, Reactivity, and Spectral Properties. Lay, Magnuson, HT, Ferguson, Krausz (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - n-Localization in Aromatic Ligands: Formation of Mixed-Metal….Harman and Taube (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - "The Reactivity of Pentaamineosmium(II) with Benzene" Harman/Taube (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Interaction of Dioxygen Species and Metal Ions—Equilibrium Aspects. PROGRESS IN INORG. CHEMISTRY (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - The Synthesis, Characterization, and Reactions of the Metal-Metal Bonded Metallocene Dimer. M. Droege, T. Smith, D. Harman, JACS (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - The Enthalpy of Substitution of NO+(aq) on Aquopentaamineruthenium(II). JF Wishart, H. Taube, S. Isied, K. Breslauer (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Coordination Chemistry and Redox Properties of Polypyridyl Complexes of Vanadim (II) Dobson and Taube (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Higher Oxidation State Chemistry of Osmocene. Droege, Harman, Taube. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Electron Transfer Reactions, Meyer/Taube, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Solvent Effects on the Reactivity of V(II). Dobson and Taube. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - "Intramolecular Electron Transfer through Isomeric Forms of Dicyanobenzene" Schaafer and Taube (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Facile Nucleophilic Substitution on Coordinated….COMMUNICATION. Kirchner and Taube (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Synthesis, Characterization, and Reactivity of the (n2-Acetone) Pentaammineosmium(II) Complex. Harman, Fairlie, Taube. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - The Preparation and Characterization of the Disulfur Bridged Os(IV) Bis-Osmocene Complex, [(Cp2OsS)2][PF6]2, Taube and Droege (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Redox Coupled Linkage Isomerizations with n2- Coordinated Anilines, Harman and Taube (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Alykne Addition-Reactions on Pentaammineosmium(II): The Formation of… Harman, Dobson, and Taube (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - cis-Bis(2,2'-bipyridine-N,N' Complexes of Ruthenium(III)/(II) and Osmium (III)/(II) (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - The Stereoselective Electron Transfer Reactions of [Co(etdca)]-, [Co(pdta)]-, and [Co(cdta)]- with [Co(en)]2+. Geselowitz, Hammershoi, Taube. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - "Enthalpic Factors in the Stability of Binuclear Pentaamineruthenium(II) Complexes of Dinitrogen and Pyrazine. Wishart, Taube, Breslaur, Isied (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Synthesis of N-Heterocyclic Complexes of Os, Ru, Co, and Rh Pentaammines. Lay, Magnuson, Taube (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Crystal Structure and Pyrolysis of [(OS)NH3)5]2 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - The Regio-and Stereospecific Selective Hydrogenation of Dihapto-Coordinated Arenes. Harman, Schaefer, and Taube (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Effects on the Frequency and Intensity of the Stretching Vibration of the Nitrile Group on Ligation to Metal Ions. Johnson and Taube (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Former Associates
    - Abe, Motoko (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Adegite, Ale – Visiting Scholar (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Alexander, Prof. M. Dale – 1975 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Anbar, Michael (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Anderson, Charles F (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Andrade, Carlos (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Ardon, Michael (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Argarwala, U.C. (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Armor, John Nelson (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Armstrong, Richard A (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Barrett, Martha Barcalow (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Baar, Roger – Undergraduate (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Beck, Mihaly – May 1984, Hungary (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Bennett, Larry Everett (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Bennett, Larry Everett, "Metalloprotein Redox Reactions" (Box 8, Folder 24)